KEVIN IM

SUPPLY CHAIN AND LOGISTICS MANAGER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

145 Picadilly Pl San Bruno, CA 94066

PHONE

650-288-7885

EMAIL

kevin.im213@gmail.com

SKILLS

Communication and Negotiation

• • • •

Organizational and planning skills

• • • • •

Inventory management

• • • • •

Ability to multitask

• • • •

Excel

• • • •

LANGUAGES

Korean

• • • •

LINKS

LinkedIn

PROFILE

Dependable logistics management specialist with 5+ years of expertise in logistics. Managed and coordinated all aspects of inbound and outbound shipments via ocean, rail, and air transportation. Experienced with RFQs and RFPs. Possesses superior organizational and planning skills, excellent in relationship building, negotiation, communication, and knowledgeable of relevant logistics and supply chain software, such as ERP, WMS, and TMS.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Logistics Operation Specialist, SF Bay Coffee

Lincoln, CA

Aug 2020 — Present

- Negotiate contracts and freight rates with ocean carriers and vendors to coordinate most cost effective means to import and to export goods
- Oversaw an annual budget (ocean freight, drayage, and domestic rail shipments) of \$4MM and cut cost by 9 percent
- · Prepare and process RFQ's, RFI's, RFP's to reduce cost shipping products
- Manage a team consisting of 12 people importing and exporting 900 TEU of merchant goods per year
- Review performances and establish relationships with supply chain vendors and 3PL companies such as DSV, XPO Logistics, and JB Hunt
- Strengthen relationships with major ocean carriers, such as MSC, Hapag-Lloyd, CMA CGM, MSC, and Hamburg Sud
- · Highly knowledgeable of incoterms and freight forwarding terms
- A project leader in setting up automation machine to increase efficiency and to reduce operation cost
- · Timely prepare import and export documentations to meet shipping schedule
- Make an annual visit to Costco in New Jersey to resolve any escalation and to ensure outstanding services

Production Associate, Tesla

Sparks, NV

May 2018 — Jul 2019

- Nominated as a workstation trainer for the battery pack assembly line training new employees to perform the complex operation using the automated equipment
- Closely performed quality control and maintained quality passing rate of 98% on 500 battery packs produced per shift
- Identify abnormalities in the manufacturing process and use root-cause analysis to diagnose issues
- Improved manufacturing procedures by presenting ideas to reduce cost in labor while increasing production output and improve quality of the product by 15%
- Troubleshoot functional and process failures prior to escalating to the appropriate support team
- · Performed 5S during downtime and consistently met production goals

CA

Mar 2015 — Apr 2018

- Work cross functionally in a group consisting of sales, logistics coordinators, and an operations manager to construct logistics plan for customers
- Experienced and excellent in using relevant software programs such as, ERP, TMS, and WMS to track deliveries and perform inventory management processes
- Experienced with shipping dangerous goods such as lithium ion batteries from Samsung SDI and LG Chem
- Highly knowledgeable of incoterms and freight forwarding terms and procedures of importing and exporting by air and ocean
- Timely create and process documentations to facilitate transporting shipments on time
- Contact freight carriers to obtain and negotiate most cost effective and efficient shipping method adhering to import and export requirements
- Participated in monthly cycle counting for warehouse and shop to ensure accountability of inventory
- · Certified to handle and ship dangerous goods by air
- · Built outstanding relationship with customers as their 3PL partner

Solutions Specialist, Verizon

South San Francisco,

CA

Nov 2013 — Mar 2015

- Worked effectively in a team environment composed of a supervisor and assistant manager by reviewing sales progress and strategies to accomplish monthly sales targets and daily goals
- Received training on daily basis to be up to date with constantly evolving products, pricing plans, promotion, and services
- Educated and trained customers with understanding of the functionality of the products and services
- · Met and excelled sales quota and metrics presented by the company
- Ensured excellent customer service by maintaining highest degree of professionalism and courtesy to resolve phone inquiries from billing issues, payments, and service charges

EDUCATION

Economics, University of California - Davis

Davis, CA

Sep 2010 — Sep 2013

REFERENCES

Regional Branch Manager John Lee from FNS, Inc.

hyesung.lee@fnsusa.com | 650-279-8426

National Retail Partner Ernesto Hernandez from Verizon Wireless

650-288-2082